[car door closes]
HEY.
ARE YOU MR. BLACK?
YEAH.
YOU SCARED ME.
[chuckles] YEAH.
SO...
I JUST...
TELL ME WHY I'M HERE.
I HAVE SOMETHING I NEED DONE.
SO DO MOST WOMEN. YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO BE MORE SPECIFIC.
RIGHT. YES. SORRY.
UM, WHAT I NEED...
I DON'T KNOW
QUITE HOW TO PUT IT.
WELL, YOU'RE JUST GONNA
HAVE TO OPEN YOUR MOUTH
AND SAY IT OUT LOUD
IN FULL DETAIL,
LIKE YOU'RE TALKING
TO YOUR PRIEST.
YOU SHOW ME YOURS.
I'LL SHOW YOU MINE.
THAT'S HOW IT WORKS.
OKAY.
HERE.
I WANT YOU TO KILL HIM.
HOW MUCH DO YOU CHARGE?
[police radio chatter]
WE THINK SHE WAS KILLED
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
NEIGHBOR HEARD SCREAMING,
CALLED 9-1-1.
ANYBODY SEE ANYTHING?WE'VE GOT SAC P.D. CANVASSING,
BUT SO FAR NOTHING--
JUST AN AVERAGE NIGHT.
AVERAGE NIGHT,
AVERAGE NEIGHBORHOOD,
AVERAGE MURDER.
WHY ARE WE HERE?
BECAUSE THE VICTIM IS ASSISTANT
DISTRICT ATTORNEY KELLY FLOWER.
YOU WORKED WITH HER.YEAH, WE ALL DID.
KELLY WAS GOOD PEOPLE.
FORENSICS FOUND A CASING.
SAID IT WAS 9-MIL.
ALMOST POINT-BLANK,
JUDGING FROM THE STIPPLING.
DEPUTY CORONER
SAID NO SEXUAL ASSAULT,
BUT HER NIGHTGOWN'S
RIPPED AND TANGLED.SHE WAS CRAWLING IN IT.
REMODEL?
KELLY'S ONE OF US. HIGHTOWER'S
ALREADY APPROVED THE OVERTIME.
YOU KNOW THE DRILL.WHY IS THAT THE DRILL?
I MEAN, FOR EVERYONE ELSE,
IT JUST LOOKS LIKE FOR YOUR OWN,
YOU TRY HARDER.
WE DO.IT'S A DETERRENT.
IT SENDS OUT A MESSAGE--NOBODY
GETS AWAY WITH KILLING A COP,
A JUDGE OR A D.A.CHO CAN GET A LIST
OF KELLY'S CASES,
SEE WHO SHE PUT AWAY
THAT HELD A GRUDGE.IT'S NOT A DETERRENT.
IT'S REVENGE, REALLY.
I MEAN,
AND THAT'S NOT A CRITICISM,
'CAUSE I'M ALL ABOUT REVENGE.
I MEAN, REVENGE CAN BE
VERY PRODUCTIVE.PRODUCTIVE?
WELL, TAKE RIGSBY.
VAN PELT BREAKS UP WITH HIM.
NOW HE'S IN THE BEST SHAPE
OF HIS LIFE.
I MEAN, HE'S HITTING THE GYM,
WHAT, SIX TIMES A WEEK?
LOOK AT HIM. HE IS BRIMMING
WITH SEXUAL CONFIDENCE.JANE, CUT IT OUT.
[Van Pelt] NOT ON MY ACCOUNT.
IT'S FINE.
SEE? FINE. MY POINT--THERE IS
NOTHING WRONG WITH REVENGE.
VAN PELT, ANY DAMAGE TO
THE WINDOWS OR THE BACK DOOR?
NO, NOTHING.NO SIGN OF FORCED ENTRY,
SO EITHER SHE LET HIM IN, OR...
[Rigsby] HUSBAND'S HERE.HE LET HIMSELF IN.
OH, MY GOD! NO!
KELLY, NO!
NO! [crying]
NO! GOD, NO!
TIFFANY WANTS YOU
TO CALL HER BACK.OH, THANKS.
SAID TO TELL YOU
YOU'RE A VERY BAD BOY.
DID SHE?
AGENT HIGHTOWER, HI.MORNING.
YOU TWO KNOW MARC ODENTHAL
FROM THE D.A.'s OFFICE?SURE. HEY.
[Cho] HI.WE'RE GONNA TALK
WITH THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME
ABOUT KELLY'S CASE?WE'RE LOOKING AT ANYBODY
WHO HAD ACCESS TO THE HOUSE
FROM WORK, THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
THE LOCAL DOG PARK, ANYWHERE.HUSBAND?
FLOWER WAS TOO UPSET
TO TALK LAST NIGHT.
JANE AND I ARE HEADING
OVER THERE NOW.AND WE'VE GOT A LIST
OF PAST DEFENDANTS.
AT LEAST FOUR HAVE EXPRESSED
WRITTEN OR VERBAL THREATS.THE D.A. TOLD ME
TO GIVE YOU THIS.
IT INCLUDES HER CURRENT CASES.HANG ON. HANK DRABER.
THE SMUGGLER?
SMUGGLING DRUGS,
CONSPIRACY TO MURDER.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO LAY A GLOVE ON 'EM BEFORE.
DRABER'S TRIAL WAS SUPPOSED
TO START NEXT WEEK.
I JUST GOT JUDGE HILDRED
TO GRANT A CONTINUANCE.
IT'S GONNA TAKE ME THREE MONTHS
JUST TO LEARN THE FILE.GO. TAKE VAN PELT.
[Cho] ALL RIGHT.
[ship horn blowing]
THERE HE IS.
MR. DRABER!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
SO HOW ARE YOU GETTING
ALONG LATELY? ANY PROBLEMS?
YOU...
MY WIFE IS DEAD, AND YOU'RE
WASTING YOUR TIME ON ME?
MR. FLOWER,
I KNEW YOUR WIFE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FIND OUT
WHO DID THIS, EVEN IF IT'S YOU.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
SO HOW WERE YOU TWO
GETTING ALONG?
[voice breaking]
WE LOVED EACH OTHER.
EVERYTHING WAS GOOD.
HOW WAS THE REMODEL?
THAT CAN BE STRESSFUL.
THINGS WERE GOOD.
BUT THAT DAY, WE FOUGHT.
THAT'S WHY I WENT
TO THE MOVIES--
OVER HER HOURS. IT...
[exhales]
IT WAS JUST SO STUPID.
SHE WAS SO STRESSED OVER
THAT DRABER CASE, YOU KNOW?
SHE CALLED IT
HER "CAREER-MAKER."
THAT'S WHAT SHE SAID--
"CAREER-MAKER."
SO YOU ARGUED.
DID IT TURN PHYSICAL?
NO. I LOVED HER.
I WOULD NEVER DO ANYTHING
LIKE THAT. NEVER.[door creaks open]
MR. FLOWER?
I GOT THE TARP ON THE ROOF
IN CASE IT RAINS
BEFORE YOU WANT ME BACK.
DIDN'T MEAN TO INTERRUPT.
I'LL GET OUT OF YOUR HAIR NOW.
THANK YOU. THAT'S
OUR CONTRACTOR CALE SYLVAN.
HE'S, UH--PATRICK JANE.
HOW YOU DOING?GOOD. YOU'RE STANDING
IN THE...
CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
UH, WOULD YOU RECOMMEND
A FLASH HOT WATER HEATER
OVER A REGULAR ONE?
I MEAN, I WAS LEANING
TOWARDS FLASH,
BUT THEY'RE VERY EXPENSIVE.WELL, YOU KNOW, FLASH WILL PAY
FOR ITSELF IN ENERGY SAVINGS
PRETTY QUICK,
BUT IT DEPENDS ON CONSUMPTION.OF COURSE.
THAT'S A VERY GOOD POINT.
UM, DO YOU HAVE A CARD?SURE.
GREAT.
I'LL MAYBE GIVE YOU A CALL.GREAT.
WELL, THANKS FOR
YOUR TIME, MR. FLOWER.
THANK YOU.
CALE SYLVAN IS
A DANGEROUS PSYCHOPATH,
AND HE KILLED KELLY FLOWER.OH? HOW'S THAT?
HE HAD ACCESS,
AND HE LOOKED EVIL.AND...
WHEN I TOLD HIM HE WAS
STANDING IN HER BLOOD,
WHAT WAS HIS REACTION?
NOT HORROR. NOT EMBARRASSMENT.
NO EMOTION AT ALL.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL RUN HIM.
EXCELLENT. HAVING PRINTS
MIGHT HELP, NO?
YOU KNOW, YOU GUYS
SHOULD BE MORE CAREFUL.
YOU ALMOST GOT YOURSELVES SHOT.
IT'S A GOOD THING
YOU LOOK LIKE COPS.
WE COULD TAKE YOU IN,
BUT YOU'LL LAWYER UP,
AND WE'LL ALL WASTE
A LOT OF TIME.
BUT HERE WE CAN HAVE
A NICE CONVERSATION, RIGHT?YEAH. THAT SOUNDS REASONABLE.
FINE. KELLY FLOWER WAS ALL SET
TO FRY YOUR ASS IN COURT.
YOU WERE LOOKING
AT 20 YEARS, EASY.
NOW THE TRIAL'S BEEN POSTPONED
WHO KNOWS HOW LONG.
THAT GIVES YOU MOTIVE
FOR HER MURDER.OH! THAT ONE'S A WINNER.
I KNOW IT IS. [grunts]
HERE YOU GO.
YOU LIKE THE LOTTO, HUH?
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS. MOM.COME ON.
YOU HAVE PRETTY HAIR.
MY MOM'S A LITTLE SENILE.NOW WHO'D TAKE CARE
OF YOUR MOTHER
IF KELLY FLOWER
PUT YOU IN JAIL?
YOU KNOW, KILLING A PROSECUTOR
IS--IS ALMOST AS BAD
AS KILLING A COP, RIGHT?
IT'S NOT SOMETHING I WANT TO
GET MY HANDS DIRTY WITH.
I GOT ENOUGH PROBLEMS
AS IT IS. RIGHT, MOM?CLOSE YOUR MOUTH, MUFFIN.
WELL, JANE'S RIGHT.
SYLVAN IS A KILLER.
OH! YOU KNOW,
IT FEELS GOOD TO BE RIGHT.
PRINTS BROUGHT UP THESE I.D.s.
WE GOT CARL SENNETT,
A WITNESS IN AN ACCIDENTAL
DROWNING IN ARIZONA,
CORY SAMPSON,
WHO LIVED NEXT DOOR
TO A HIT-AND-RUN VICTIM
IN SEATTLE,
AND CHAD SEWELL,
WANTED FOR QUESTIONING
ABOUT THE MURDER OF HIS BOSS,
A BANK EXECUTIVE IN RENO.
WE HAVE FOUR OTHER DEATHS
THAT SYLVAN'S LINKED TO
IN SOME OTHER WAY.HE'S NOT JUST A KILLER.
HE'S A SERIAL KILLER.
WELL, SADDLE UP.
LOCK AND LOAD. DO WHAT YOU DO.
GO--GO BRING HIM IN.WE CAN'T.
NOPE.WHAT?
ALL WE HAVE IS THAT CALE SYLVAN
LIKED TO CHANGE HIS NAME--
NOT ILLEGAL--AND THAT
BAD LUCK FOLLOWED HIM.
WE DON'T EVEN HAVE ENOUGH
FOR A SEARCH WARRANT.HE'LL KILL AGAIN. YOU--
YOU KNOW WHAT HE IS, LISBON.
KNOWING ISN'T PROVING.
RIGSBY, HAVE CHO SET UP
ON SYLVAN'S HOUSE
24-HOUR SURVEILLANCE.
IF HE SHOWS UP, HAVE CHO FOLLOW
HIM. MAYBE WE'LL GET LUCKY.OKAY.
THIS--THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I...
I KNOW.I'M GONNA GO WITH CHO. CHO!
GO.
SYLVAN'S SMART ENOUGH
TO KNOW WE'LL BE HERE.
HE WON'T BE COMING BACK.
IT'S A WASTE OF TIME.
YEP.
WHAT ARE YOU READING
THERE, CHO?"WUTHERING HEIGHTS."
WELL,
I'M GONNA TAKE A STROLL.
LET ME KNOW HOW IT ENDS.
NOT WELL.
[knocks on door]CHO SAID JANE DITCHED HIM
AT SYLVAN'S. HAVE YOU SEEN HIM?
NOPE. THERE'S SOMETHING HINKY
HERE, BOSS.
THESE ARE PHOTOS OF SOME OF
THE VICTIMS LINKED TO SYLVAN.
DIFFERENT AGES,
SEXES, RACES.EXACTLY.
A SERIAL KILLER ALMOST ALWAYS
HUNTS THE SAME KIND OF PREY.
THIS DOESN'T MAKE SENSE
AS A SERIAL KILLER'S M.O.IT DOES WHEN YOU LOOK
AT SYLVAN'S FINANCIALS.
I TRACKED BANK RECORDS FOR
ALL THE I.D.s WE COULD FIND.
SYLVAN RECEIVED
SUBSTANTIAL PAYMENTS
JUST BEFORE
AND JUST AFTER EACH DEATH.HE KILLS FOR MONEY?
HE'S A HIT MAN?
A PSYCHOPATH WHO MADE MONEY
FROM HIS HOBBY.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
YOU DO SOMETHING YOU LOVE.
YOU NEVER HAVE TO WORK
A DAY IN YOUR LIFE.WHERE THE HELL HAVE YOU BEEN?
ME? OH, I'VE BEEN AROUND.I FOUND A WEB SITE REGISTERED
TO ONE OF HIS OLD IDENTITIES.
IT SAYS TO "CALL MR. BLACK
FOR ODD JOBS OF ANY SORT."
WELL, I GUESS
WE SHOULD GIVE HIM A CALL.
UH. GRACE, DO YOU HAPPEN
TO HAVE ANY PHOTOGRAPHS
OF, UH, YOU KNOW,
EX-BOYFRIENDS?
I WANT YOU TO KILL HIM.
HOW MUCH DO YOU CHARGE?
ASK HIM AGAIN, GRACE.
YOU'RE A BUSY LADY.
YOU DON'T HAVE ALL NIGHT.
YOU GONNA ANSWER ME OR NOT?
I WANT THE BASTARD DEAD--SOON.OOH. SHE'S CONVINCING.
SHH. TRYING TO WORK HERE.
OKAY.
I CHARGE $50,000.
AND WHAT YOU'RE ASKING
IS PRETTY EASY.
I MEAN,
YOU JUST GOTTA HAVE
TO STOP THINKING OF HIM
AS A PERSON.
THE REST IS JUST A PHYSICS
PROBLEM--GRAVITY, FORCE, TORQUE.
ASK FOR PROOF OF WHAT HE DOES.
TORQUE IS WELL AND GOOD,
BUT I NEED TO KNOW
THAT YOU'RE FOR REAL.
SEE, MAYBE YOU'RE A HITTER.
MAYBE YOU'RE A COP.
LONG SHOT.SHH! TRYING TO WORK HERE.
LET ME SHOW YOU SOMETHIN'.
HOW'S THAT?
LET'S MOVE.NO, NO, NO. IT'S A TEST. GRACE,
LISTEN. LISTEN VERY CAREFULLY.
ARE YOU A COP?
I'M NOT A COP.
NO?
I'M JUST CAREFUL,
LIKE YOU.
UH-HUH.
I JUST WANT TO KNOW
THAT I HAVE THE RIGHT MAN.
BESIDES, DON'T YOU WANT
TO SHOW ME...
BESIDES,
DON'T YOU WANT TO SHOW ME,
SO YOU CAN MAKE ME AFRAID?
THAT'S WHAT YOU LIKE,
ISN'T IT--
SEEING THE FEAR?
YOU SHOW ME YOURS,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU MINE.
I HAVE SOMETHING TO SHOW YOU THEN.
JUST WATCH FOR A SECOND. [Kelly shouts indistinctly]
OH, WAIT. OH, PLEASE!
LOOK AT IT.
IT'S MY LAST JOB. PLEASE!
[muffled gunshot] AAH!
THE CLIENT WAS VERY HAPPY.PROOF. THAT'S PROOF.
PROOF.
ARE WE GONNA DO BUSINESS?
YES, WE ARE.
CBI![Lisbon] DROP THE KNIFE!
DON'T MOVE!
HANDS ON YOUR HEAD![sirens wailing]
[Lisbon] DROP THE KNIFE NOW!DON'T MOVE!
ON YOUR KNEES!CALE SYLVAN, YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDER OF KELLY FLOWER.
[police radio chatter]
HANDS ON YOUR HEAD!
JANE, YOU CAN COME OUT.[Patrick] OKAY.
HOW'D YOU KNOW HE HAD PROOF?
WELL, HE'S A NARCISSIST.
NEEDS AFFIRMATION, TROPHIES.
WHO PAID YOU TO KILL KELLY?
TELL 'EM.
YOU'LL FEEL BETTER.I WOULD LIKE
TO TALK TO MY LAWYER.
[police radio chatter]
AND I'LL SEE
YOU CLOWNS IN COURT.
CATCHING KILLERS I ENJOY,
BUT BEING REMINDED
THAT WE'RE JUST A COG
IN A PETTY, FASCIST MACHINE--
THAT IS A LITTLE DEPRESSING.
CRIME-FIGHTING IS HARD.
SUCK IT UP.
IF YOU WEREN'T
ON THE WITNESS LIST,
I WOULDN'T EVEN LET YOU
IN THE SAME TIME ZONE
AS JUDGE DREAD.
"JUDGE DREAD"--CAN'T POSSIBLY
BE AS MUCH FUN AS IT SOUNDS.
[Sylvan speaks indistinctly] OH, PLEASE! PLEASE!
WHAT DO YOU WANT? OH, GOD!
OH, GOD, DON'T HURT ME!
OH, GOD! OH, GOD, DON'T!
PLEASE! PLEASE! OHH! [muffled shot fires]
YOUR HONOR, I OBJECT.
THIS VIDEO IS INFLAMMATORY
AND PREJUDICIAL.
ALTHOUGH WE'LL STIPULATE
TO THE FACT
THAT KELLY FLOWER WAS MURDERED,
WE RESERVE OUR RIGHT TO DENY
THAT THERE IS PROBABLE CAUSE
MY CLIENT COMMITTED SAID MURDER.
AND WE ALSO OBJECT TO THE CHAIN
OF CUSTODY FOR THIS VIDEO.WOW. IS THAT EVEN A SENTENCE?
QUIET IN THE GALLERY!
YOU SAY ANOTHER WORD,
AND YOU'LL REGRET IT.WELL, I'M--I'M SORRY,
YOUR HONOR, BUT THIS WOMAN
IS SPOUTING NOTHING
BUT LUDICROUS PETTIFOGGERY,
AND, UH, I'M A LITTLE HUNGRY.YOUR HONOR, IF YOU'LL LET ME
DOWN, I CAN HANDLE HIM.
MR. JANE--
THAT IS YOUR NAME, CORRECT?
THAT'S CORRECT. PATRICK JANE.
WELL, THIS COURT HEREBY FINES
YOU $1,000.MAKE IT $2,000,
AND LET ME TELL THIS, UH,
TIRESOME WOMAN TO MOVE IT ALONG.
$2,000 THEN.OKAY.
COUNSELOR, YOU HEARD THE MAN.
MOVE IT ALONG.
SO, AGENT LISBON,
LET'S GET BACK TO THIS VIDEO.
THAT NIGHT WAS THE FIRST TIME
YOU'D EVER SEEN IT?YES.
ARE YOU SURE?OBJECTION.
ASKED AND ANSWERED.
I'LL MOVE ON, YOUR HONOR.
SO YOU NEVER ENTERED
MR. SYLVAN'S APARTMENT
AND LOOKED AT THE VIDEO
ON HIS COMPUTER OR INSTRUCTED
ANYONE ELSE TO DO SO?NO.
WELL, THEN I NEED YOU TO ANSWER
A PUZZLING QUESTION.
YOUR HONOR, I WOULD LIKE
TO ENTER THIS INTO EVIDENCE
AS DEFENSE EXHIBIT ONE.
UH-OH.
I GOT THIS MUG
FROM MR. SYLVAN'S SINK.
BUT HE DIDN'T PUT IT THERE.SO...
SO TELL ME,
HOW IS IT THAT THIS MUG
HAS MR. JANE'S
FINGERPRINTS ON IT?
AGENT LISBON,
DID YOUR CONSULTANT
BREAK INTO MR. SYLVAN'S HOME
WITHOUT A WARRANT?NO. NO, OF COURSE NOT.
YOUR HONOR, MAY I HAVE A MOMENT
TO CONFER WITH AGENT LISBON?
YOU MAKE IT QUICK.
THIS IS GETTING INTERESTING.
BAILIFF.
[whispering] THAT'S HOW
YOU KNEW SYLVAN HAD PROOF.
YOU'D ALREADY SEEN IT.[whispering] I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED NOW.
[lowers voice]
I WAS WITH CHO.
WE WERE STAKING OUT
SYLVAN'S PLACE.
I DECIDED I WANTED
TO TAKE A WALK.
I HAPPENED UPON SYLVAN'S DOOR,
UNLOCKED.
AND LIKE
ANY CONCERNED CITIZEN,
I WENT IN TO LOOK AROUND
AND CHECKED THAT THE PLACE
HADN'T BEEN ROBBED.
THEN I LEFT.
THAT'S IT.
OH, CRAP.
WHAT'S THE STORY,
MR. ODENTHAL?
YOUR HONOR... [clears throat]
MR. JANE DID ENTER
MR. SYLVAN'S RESIDENCE,
BUT ONLY BECAUSE HE FEARED
THERE WAS AN INTRUDER INSIDE.
YOU MEAN ONE BESIDES HIMSELF?I-IT'S NOT LIKE
I TOOK ANYTHING, YOUR HONOR.
YOUR HONOR,
WHAT MR. JANE IS TRYING TO SAY
IS THAT HE'S NOT A STATE AGENT.
HE'S A PRIVATE CONSULTANT.
THEREFORE, THERE'S NO
FOURTH AMENDMENT VIOLATION.
MR. JANE IS A CHARLATAN
WHO HAS MADE A MOCKERY
OF OUR LEGAL SYSTEM
ON NUMEROUS OCCASIONS.
IN FACT, A FEW MONTHS AGO
HE REFUSED TO TAKE A WOMAN
TO THE HOSPITAL FOR POISONING
UNTIL SHE CONFESSED TO A MURDER.SHE WAS NOT POISONED
IN THE FIRST PLACE,
AND IT WAS JUST
A VERY CLEVER RUSE--QUIET, MR. JANE.
FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH.YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED
OF YOURSELF ANYWAY.
YOU, TOO, AGENT LISBON.
YOU'RE THE LAW.
I HOLD MR. JANE'S SEARCH
TO BE ILLEGAL,
AND ANY EVIDENCE DISCOVERED
THEN OR DURING THE STING
IS HEREBY EXCLUDED AS FRUIT
OF THE POISONOUS TREE.
THE VIDEO--OUT.
ANY STATEMENTS
MADE BY THE DEFENDANT
TO AGENT VAN PELT--OUT.YOUR HONOR, I OBJECT.
YOUR ANGER IS CLOUDING YOUR--
MR. ODENTHAL, DO YOU HAVE
ANY EVIDENCE OF ANY KIND
THAT YOUR CONSULTANT
HASN'T CRAPPED ALL OVER?
[sighs]
NO, YOUR HONOR.
WELL,
THEN THE PEOPLE v. SYLVAN
IS HEREBY DISMISSED
FOR LACK OF EVIDENCE.
MR. SYLVAN,
YOU'RE FREE TO GO.[bang]
THIS IS RIDICULOUS,
YOUR HONOR.
THIS IS WRONG!
THIS DON'T MAKE NO SENSE!
I'LL BE SEEING YOU.
HE KILLED MY WIFE!
HOW CAN HE GO FREE?
[Judge Hildred] BAILIFF,
BRING IN THE NEXT CASE.
I HAD A CONFESSION.
I HAD VIDEO.
I HAD AN AIRTIGHT CASE.
AND IT'S ALL OUT.
HOW COULD YOU BREAK
INTO HIS PLACE?EASY. THE LOCK ON THE BACK DOOR
WAS VERY FLIMSY.
MARC, I APOLOGIZE. I DO. I--ALSO, I DIDN'T THINK
I'D BE FOUND OUT.
I MEAN, HOW WAS I TO KNOW
THEY WERE GOING TO DUST
FOR MYFINGERPRINTS?YOU LET A KILLER
BACK ON THE STREETS.
ACTUALLY, I GOT THE KILLER
OFF THE STREETS.
KEEPING HIM OFF THE STREETS--
YOUR JOB.YOU'RE BLAMING ME?
I'M NOT THE ONE WHO GOT
THE MURDER WEAPON TOSSED.COURT IS THEATER. WHATEVER SIDE
HAS THE BEST LIAR WINS.
USUALLY THAT'S YOU,
BUT TODAY SHE WAS BETTER.
YOU'RE AN ARROGANT
LITTLE BASTARD.WHOA, EASY WITH THE STEEL,
BROTHER.
OH, RELAX. IT'S NOT LOADED.
LOOK, MARC, THERE IS
NO DOUBLE JEOPARDY HERE.
WE CAN STILL
TAKE THIS TO TRIAL.
I WILL FIND NEW EVIDENCE.
I PROMISE.
YOU'RE A MENACE.
WHEN I'M D.A., YOU'LL NEVER
WORK WITH THIS OFFICE AGAIN.
SO AMBITIOUS.NOT YOUR CALL, MARC.
NOT THEN, NOT NOW.
YOU'RE DEFENDING HIM?THANK YOU, LISBON.
SHUT UP, JANE.
I THOUGHT YOU TWO
TRUSTED EACH OTHER.
SO DID I.
WE DO. I--WE HAVE TRUST.
I-I DIDN'T TELL HER
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT HER
TO BE COMPLICIT AND THEN
HAVE TO LIE ABOUT IT LATER.
SOME PARTNERSHIP
YOU GOT GOING ON HERE.
I'LL HAVE TO SEND YOU HOME WHILE
THE PROFESSIONAL STANDARDS UNIT
DOES ITS THING--
FIVE DAYS AT LEAST.WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
IT'S NOT HER FAULT.
THAT WILL BE THE P.S.U.'s
DETERMINATION, NO DOUBT.
THIS IS JUST THE SITUATION
WE TALKED ABOUT, PATRICK.
AGENT LISBON IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE ACTIONS OF HER TEAM MEMBERS,
INCLUDING YOU.
YES, MA'AM.
IS THAT ALL?YES.
[lowers voice] LOOK,
LISBON, I'M SO SORRY.
I REALLY AM.
JANE.
LISBON NEEDS SOME TIME OFF.
A FEW DAYS OFF
WILL DO HER GOOD.
NICE TALKING WITH YOU.
YEAH.
RIGSBY, GO BACK THROUGH
SYLVAN'S FINANCIALS.
VAN PELT, TAKE ANOTHER LOOK
AT KELLY'S VIDEO OF HER MURDER.
SEE IF WE MISSED ANYTHING.
HEY, WE'LL SERVE UP SYLVAN
AS YOUR WELCOME BACK PRESENT,
OKAY?
OOH. IT'S A LITTLE CHILLY
IN HERE.
DO YOU WANT TO GO
GET A COFFEE?
OH, COME ON.
LOOK AT THE BRIGHT SIDE.
YOU GET FIVE DAYS OFF.
YOU GET FIVE DAYS OFF FROM ME.
CHO, YOU'RE IN CHARGE.
HE'S YOUR PROBLEM NOW.
THAT'S GOOD. CHO'S A BIG BOY.
HE KNOWS HOW TO LOOK AFTER ME.
YOU WANT TO GET A COFFEE?
DID YOU BRING A BOOK?
COULD BE A BIT OF A WAIT.
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
YOU'RE STILL MAD WITH ME
ABOUT LISBON'S SUSPENSION.
YEAH. IT'S YOUR FAULT.
YEAH. YOU KNOW,
MURDERERS TAKE RISKS.
SOMETIMES IN ORDER
TO CATCH THESE RISK TAKERS,
WE HAVE TO TAKE RISKS.
THERE CAN BE FALLOUT.TELL ME WHAT'S GOING ON
OR I'M OUTTA HERE.
[lowers voice] OKAY. I LOOKED
IN SYLVAN'S KITCHEN CABINETS.
NOT MUCH OF A TEA SELECTION.
HE'S A COFFEE GEEK--
DRINKS ONLY THE BEST,
FRESH-ROAST COFFEE.
AND THE BEST
FRESH-ROASTED COFFEE
IN SYLVAN'S NEIGHBORHOOD...IS IN THIS PLACE HERE.
THAT'S KIND OF THIN.
YEAH, BUT I'M 100%
CONFIDENT THAT IT...[door bells jingle]
THANK GOODNESS.
[lowers voice] LOOK,
THE JUDGE WARNED US NOT TO TALK
TO SYLVAN WITHOUT HIS LAWYER.TALK? THIS IS TWO GUYS
BUMPING INTO EACH OTHER
IN THE COFFEE LINE.
JANE.
CALE?
OH!
THAT'S A FUNNY COINCIDENCE.
I TOLD YOU
I'D BE SEEING YOU.
YEAH.MM.
WELL, YOU LOOK WELL,
I GOTTA SAY.
YOU'RE IN
A VERY RELAXED STATE.
NOW CONFESS THAT
YOU KILLED KELLY FLOWER,
AND A HUGE BURDEN
WILL BE LIFTED.
FUNNY GUY.
SENSE OF HUMOR. THAT'S GREAT.
YEAH. WELL,
MAYBE I DID SOMETHING WRONG.MM.
SORRY TO, UH, BOTHER YOU.ACCIDENTS HAPPEN.
YEAH.
[clears throat]
HYPNOSIS. GREAT PLAN.
[lowers voice]
NO, THAT WOULD BE SILLY.
HYPNOSIS IS ILLEGAL.
THAT WAS A MISDIRECT SO THAT I
COULD SEARCH HIS JACKET POCKETS
AND FIND... [whispers] THIS.
A BUTTON,
FLUFF AND SOME SAND?
YEAH.
IT'S A LITTLE ANTICLIMACTIC.
UM, DO YOU HAVE
AN EVIDENCE BAGGIE?
[clears throat]
YOU'RE WALKING HOME.
OR I COULD JUST CARRY IT.
SO SYLVAN'S FINANCIALS
ARE CLEAN.
THERE'S JUST ONE THING
I DON'T GET.
THE END OF EVERY MONTH,
HE WITHDRAWS
JUST OVER 2 GRAND IN CASH.
HE HAS NO FAMILY,
NO GIRLFRIEND.SOUNDS LIKE RENT.
HIS APARTMENT'S ONLY $900,
AND HE WRITES A CHECK FOR THAT.NO, NOT HIS APARTMENT--
HIS HOME.
A PLACE TO STORE HIS TOOLS,
PROCESS HIS VICTIMS,
KEEP HIS TROPHIES.A MURDER HOUSE. AND IF HE'S
PAYING CASH, IT'S A FAIR BET
THE NAME CALE SYLVAN
WON'T BE ON THE LEASE.
THE PLACE COULD BE ANYWHERE.MAYBE I CAN NARROW IT
A LITTLE. LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS FROM
THE SYLVAN MURDER VIDEO.[presses keys]
THE BAG HE'S HOLDING--
IT'S FROM ABS GYM.
WE SHOW HIS PICTURE
AROUND THE GYM.
MAYBE WE FIND SOMEONE
WHO KNOWS HIS OTHER ADDRESS.THERE'S A DOZEN ABS GYMS
AROUND HERE.
IT'LL TAKE DAYS
TO CANVASS 'EM.I'LL START WITH THE ONES BY
THE RIVER. THE SAND JANE FOUND
IN SYLVAN'S POCKETS--
IT'S RIVER SAND, NOT OCEAN SAND.HOW'D YOU KNOW?
WE'RE IN SACRAMENTO.
WE GOT A RIVER, NOT AN OCEAN.THERE'S ONLY ONE ABS GYM
NEAR THE RIVER--ON DOS ROBLES.
[Rigsby] ON MY WAY.IF YOU GET AN ADDRESS,
GO STRAIGHT TO JUDGE HILDRED
AND GET A SEARCH WARRANT.
WE'LL TAKE DOWN SYLVAN TODAY.
[man whimpering]
AW, SHUT UP.
♪♪
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE EMBEZZLED
ALL THAT MONEY, YOU BIG BABY.
[crunches]
[gunfire]
TIME TO GO TO WORK.
[whimpering]
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE GONNA WANT
TO LOOK AT THIS.
[glass shatters]
[grunts]
[Rigsby] FREEZE! FREEZE!
[speaks indistinctly]
[Cho] LET ME SEE YOUR HANDS!
LET ME SEE YOUR HANDS!AAH!
[grunts][grunts]
[whimpers and grunts]
[grunting]
GET YOUR HANDS OFF OF ME!
GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
HOOK HIM UP.IT'S NOT ME.
I HOPE YOU BROUGHT MORE PEOPLE.
[Cale] CHEATING SON OF A BITCH.
[grunts]
YOU'RE OKAY. YOU'RE OKAY.
THANK YOU.YOU'RE SAFE NOW.
[spits]YOU GOT IT?
YEAH.THERE WE GO.
[snaps cell phone shut]
I SENT THE VICTIM
TO THE HOSPITAL.
HE'LL BE OKAY... AFTER THREE
OR FOUR YEARS OF THERAPY.GOOD.
YEAH, THAT LOOK'S NOT SO SCARY
WHEN YOU'RE IN HANDCUFFS, BUDDY.
EITHER YOU TELL US
WHO HIRED YOU
OR YOU'RE LOOKING
AT A SLAM-DUNK DEATH PENALTY.
MAYBE WE CAN COME
TO SOME KIND OF ARRANGEMENT.
CHO, GET DOWN!
[gunshot][Rigsby] 10-33. SHOTS FIRED.
MAN DOWN. WE NEED PARAMEDICS
NOW. G.S.W. TO THE CHEST.
SHOT CAME FROM THE NORTH
OF LOCATION. NORTH OF LOCATION.
LET'S GET A BIRD
IN HERE NOW.THE SON OF A BITCH IS DEAD.
CALL IN ANOTHER TEAM
FOR THE BACK OF THE HOUSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S EIGHT BODIES SO FAR,
AND THAT'S JUST THE ONES
SYLVAN'S CLIENTS
DIDN'T WANT FOUND.THEY'RE GONNA BE CLEARING
MISSING PERSONS CASES
FOR A MONTH.ANY LUCK ON THE SHOOTER?
NOT MUCH. KILL SHOT CAME
FROM THAT HILLSIDE,
OVER TWO FOOTBALL FIELDS AWAY.THAT'S A TOUGH SHOT. SO I
GUESS WHOEVER EMPLOYED SYLVAN
HIRED A SECOND SHOOTER
TO COVER HIS TRACKS.THE THING IS,
HOW DID THAT CLIENT KNOW
THAT SYLVAN HAD BECOME
A LIABILITY?THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
WHERE'S JANE?
HEY.
THIS BETTER BE GOOD.
I WAS CATCHING UP ON MY TiVo.
LIAR. YOU WERE READING.
BUT WHAT?
PROGRESS REPORTS?
NO.
WHATEVER. THIS IS
GONNA BE A LOT OF FUN.
I'M GOING INTO
THE DRABERS' LAIR.
IT'S NOT A LAIR, IT'S AN OFFICE,
AND NO, YOU'RE NOT.OH, YES, I AM.
THEY SEEM KIND OF SCARY.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT ME
TO GET HURT, WOULD YOU?
DON'T BET ON IT.
W-WHY THE DRABERS?A HUNCH.
THEY'RE KEY IN THIS SOMEHOW.
YOU THINK THEY HIRED SYLVAN?WELL,
SYLVAN LOOKED THE PART.
WHY THE HELL
DIDN'T YOU CALL CHO?
WELL, YOU WERE CLOSER.
CALL CHO.
I'M NOT EVEN ARMED.
MORE LIES. YOU HAVE AT LEAST
TWO GUNS IN THAT CAR.
THREE? OH, MY.
[groans]
YOU'RE THE POSTER GIRL
FOR THE N.R.A.
I'M TELLING YOU,
I'VE GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE PROSECUTOR DYING.
AND THE SYLVAN GUY--
NEVER HEARD OF HIM
BEFORE I SAW HIM
ON THE NEWS.HELLO.
HI.GONNA WIN BIG.
GONNA BUY A WASHING MACHINE.
SHE'S A TREASURE.
HEY. YOU WANT
TO LEAVE HER ALONE?
SHE'S A LITTLE SOFT
IN THE HEAD, OKAY?YOU KNOW, HANK, AS YOU WERE
TALKING TO LISBON HERE,
I COULDN'T HELP BUT NOTICE
YOU KEPT LOOKING AT YOUR MOTHER,
AS IF YOU WERE CHECKING
FOR HER APPROVAL.
I MEAN, MOST TOUGH GUYS ARE
SCARED OF THEIR MOTHERS,
BUT, HANK, YOU WERE QUAKING.[laughs] YOUR FRIEND'S
CRAZIER THAN MY MOM.
DIGGING THOSE NAILS.
PLUCKED EYEBROWS, COIFFED HAIR.
DID YOU DO THE, UH,
MAKEOVER, HANK?
NO, DIDN'T THINK SO.
TIME FOR MY STORIES, HANKY.
OKAY, HANKY.
YOU ARE UPSETTING HER, OKAY?
SO LEAVE HER ALONE.
EASY.
THIS IS BRILLIANT.
LISBON, THIS IS BRILLIANT.
YOU--YOU ARE A TREASURE.
YOU'RE RUNNING THIS WHOLE
OPERATION, AREN'T YOU?
HANK'S JUST A FIGUREHEAD
TO TAKE THE HEAT. HUH?
TELL ME I'M RIGHT. YOU KNOW,
I SHOULD HAVECHECKED THE SHOES.
DAMN IT, HANK.
I TOLD YOU ABOUT LOOKING AT ME,
DIDN'T I?
YOU THINK
YOU'RE SO DAMN CLEVER.
WELL, CLEVER IS
AS CLEVER DOES,
AND YOU'VE JUST MADE
A VERY STUPID MOVE.
BOYS!
OH, DEAR.
HOW CLEVER ARE YOU NOW EXACTLY?
[guns cock]WE'RE COPS. JUST BE COOL.
PUT THE WEAPONS DOWN NOW.
YOU PUT YOUR GUN DOWN,
MISS LISBON, AND YOU CAN LIVE.
COME ON. GET IN.
[Hank] OKAY, LOAD 'EM OFF.
I WAS RIGHT
ABOUT ANNABELLE ANYWAY.CONGRATULATIONS.
[whirring]
[horn honks]
OH, HEY.HEY.
SO WE'RE GOOD, RIGHT?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA PUT A HIT
OUT ON ME?
[chuckles] YOU'VE MOVED ON.
THAT'S GOOD.
I'VE MOVED ON, TOO.
WELL, I'M GLAD.
THAT'S A RELIEF.
YOU GUYS HEARD FROM JANE?
NO.NO.
HELLO?!
ANYBODY?!
I CAN'T REALLY SEE ANYTHING.
THERE'S KIND OF A DRAFT RIGHT
HERE, THOUGH, IF YOU JUST...
JUST THERE.
NO FOOD, NO WATER.
THIS IS NOT GOOD.
WELL, I SUPPOSE
WE SHOULD DRAW STRAWS
TO SEE WHO EATS WHO FIRST.
YEAH, RIGHT. DRAW STRAWS
WITH A PROFESSIONAL CHEAT.
WHY SO GRUMPY? IT'S NOT LIKE
WE'RE GONNA DIE HERE.
THE DRABERS
DON'T WANT US DEAD.
HUH?
COME HERE AND GET
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS BREEZE.
IT'LL CHEER YOU UP.
COME HERE.[sighs]
IT'S NOT QUITE AS NICE
AS A RIVER BREEZE,
BUT IT'S NOT BAD.MM.
YOU FEELING THAT?MM.
GOOD. [exhales deeply]
RIVER BREEZE.
WAIT A MINUTE. I LIVE
NOWHERE NEAR THE DOCKS.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S A TERRIBLE NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU SAID YOU CALLED ME
BECAUSE I WAS CLOSER,
BUT THE H.Q. IS
ONLY 15 MINUTES FROM THE DOCKS.
I'M--I'M JUST--I'M BAD WITH
DISTANCES, ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
PATRICK JANE,
YOU WERE TRYING TO HELP ME.
YOU WERE. YOU THOUGHT
IF I MADE A BIG BUST,
THE P.S.U. WOULD GET OFF
MY BACK.
YOU KNOW I'M ALWAYS
GONNA SAVE YOU, LISBON,
WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT.
I DON'T NEED TO BE SAVED.
I KNEW THIS WOULD END A DISASTER
THE DAY I SIGNED ON WITH YOU.
ONE DAY I'M GONNA GET FIRED
BECAUSE OF YOU.
THAT'S JUST THE WAY IT IS.
RIGHT. WELL, SOME PEOPLE MIGHT
ASK WHY YOU SIGNED ON WITH ME
IN THE FIRST PLACE.WE CATCH A LOT OF BAD GUYS.
MOST DAYS, THAT'S ENOUGH.
ALSO, I--[animal bleats]
SHH. I THINK I HEAR SOMETHING.
SOMEONE OUT THERE.WHERE?
HELLO!HELLO?
OVER HERE!IN HERE!
AROUND THE FRONT.
THE--THE BIG LATCH.
I TOLD YOU
I WOULD SAVE YOU, LISBON.[chuckles]
[Patrick] WHAT?
[bleats]
HEY.
SAC P.D. FOUND JANE'S CAR
AT THE DOCKS. LISBON'S, TOO.[whispers] CRAP.
NO SIGN OF THEM
OR THE DRABERS.CALL SAC P.D., I.C.E.
AND THE COAST GUARD.
HAVE THEM SEARCH
EVERY VEHICLE...[telephone rings]
WAREHOUSE AND BOAT
THE DRABERS OWN.VAN PELT. O-OH. SLOW DOWN.
AGENT RIGSBY.UM, Sí. UNO--UNO MOMENTO,
POR FAVOR.
CAN YOU?I'LL CALL YOU BACK.
[hangs up receiver]IT'S THE FEDERALES, I THINK.
UH...SOMETHING ABOUT JANE
AND A GOAT?
LOUISE WILLETT ROBBED
THE VERY PEOPLE SHE WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE TAKING CARE OF,
AND SHE SPENT THAT MONEY--IPSO FACTO, AD NAUSEAM.
SORRY, ODENTHAL. I NEED TO
BORROW YOUR JUDGE FOR A SECOND.
[clears throat] UH, MR. JANE,
WE ARE IN SESSION.YES, WE WOULD HAVE
COME EARLIER,
BUT, UH, WE HAD
QUITE A LONG WALK GETTING HERE.
IT WON'T TAKE A SECOND.
WE JUST NEED
ONE OF YOUR FANCY ARREST/WARRANT
THINGIES FOR ANNABELLE DRABER.[cell phone rings]
SHE'LL GIVE YOU THE DETAILS.JANE, GET OUT OF HERE.
MR. JANE, THERE ARE NO PHONES
IN MY COURTROOM.I'M VERY SORRY.
JUST A MINUTE, CHO.
THAT'S $1,000, MR. JANE.I'M KINDA BUSY. UH, SURE.
UH, LISTEN, I'M KINDA
IN THE MIDDLE OF SOMETHING,
SO I'LL CALL YOU BACK.[pounds gavel]
$2,000. HANG IT UP. NOW!REALLY?
$3,000.LISTEN, CHO, UH...
$4,000.YOUR HONOR,
I MOVE FOR A MISTRIAL.
$5,000.YOU'RE NOT COSTING ME ANOTHER
CASE. GIVE ME THAT PHONE.
NO. GET YOUR OWN.YOUR HONOR--BATTERY?
BAILIFFS, WOULD YOU ARREST
THIS MAN, PLEASE?
LISBON, THIS...
HANG ON, CHO.
I'M ON SUSPENSION.
NO BADGE, NO AUTHORITY.
[sighs]
OH, THANKS
FOR BAILING ME OUT.
LISBON WASN'T ANSWERING
HER PHONE FOR SOME REASON.
THE JUDGE IS REALLY PISSED,
SO IS ODENTHAL.
THEY WANT TO MAKE AN EXAMPLE.EH.
IT'S NOT JUST CONTEMPT OF COURT,
JANE. IT'S BATTERY.BATTERY AGAINST
A PEACE OFFICER.
PENAL CODE SECTION 242
"ET SEQ."
I LOVE THE LATIN.
YOU KNOW THERE'S 30 KINDS
OF BATTERY CHARGES?
YES.
THIS STUFF IS FASCINATING.
YOU KNOW,
I COULD BE MY OWN LAWYER.
YOU'RE GONNA REPRESENT
YOURSELF?
YOU REPRESENT YOURSELF,
YOU'RE AN IDIOT.UH, IT'S ACTUALLY
"HE WHO IS HIS OWN LAWYER
HAS A FOOL FOR A CLIENT."
IT'S MUCH CATCHIER.
COULD BE FUN, CHO.
THIS MAY BE A, UM,
A SOMEWHAT INFORMAL HEARING,
BUT YOU STILL MUST RESPECT
THIS COURT,
OR YOU WILL GO DIRECTLY
BACK TO JAIL. DO YOU READ ME?
YEAH, YOU BET, YOUR HONOR.
MR. JANE ASKED ME TO COME.
DO YOU KNOW WHY?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
LET'S GET RIGHT TO IT, MR. JANE.
IS IT TRUE THAT YESTERDAY,
YOU TWEAKED THE ASSISTANT
DISTRICT ATTORNEY'S NOSE
IN THIS VERY ROOM?
[laughs]
SPEAKING OF YOURSELF
IN THE THIRD PERSON, MARC,
Y-YOU GOTTA ADMIT,
SOUNDS A LITTLE SILLY.
YES, I TWEAKED YOUR NOSE.
YOUR HONOR, WE'RE DONE HERE.
MR. JANE ADMITS THE CRIME.
BUT IN MY DEFENSE,
YOU WERE BEING VERY ANNOYING.
MR. JANE,
YOU'RE OUT OF ORDER.[imitating Al Pacino]
YOU'RE OUT OF ORDER.
THIS WHOLE TRIAL'S OUT OF ORDER![sighs]
[normal voice] OH, COME ON.
YOU GOTTA ADMIT,
YOU WALKED RIGHT INTO THAT ONE.
[chuckles]
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
MY TURN TO QUESTION YOU GUYS.
YES. WAIT.
"YOU GUYS"? PLURAL?
WELL, YOU'RE BOTH WITNESSES.
UH... WHEN I'M
CROSS-EXAMINING MYSELF,
DO--DO I HAVE TO STAND DOWN
THERE AND ASK THE QUESTIONS
AND RUN BACK UP HERE
AND ANSWER THEM?MR. JANE, YOU STAY PUT.
OKAY.
MR. ODENTHAL,
YOU TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
PRO PERDEFENDANTS ARE GIVENA CERTAIN AMOUNT OF LATITUDE.
YOU KNOW THAT.
GOD HELP US ALL.
JUDGE HILDRED, ARE YOU NOW
OR HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
A MEMBER
OF THE COMMUNIST PARTY? WHAT?NO!
MR. ODENTHAL, DO YOU OWN A GUN?
WAIT. WHAT?ARE YOU A GOOD SHOT?
DON'T ANSWER THAT.
HOW ABOUT YOU, YOUR HONOR?
YOU ANY GOOD WITH A GUN?
THE PERSON
THAT KILLED CALE SYLVAN,
THEY ESTIMATED,
WAS MORE THAN 200 YARDS AWAY.
THAT IS A GREAT SHOT.
IT'S WHY WE ASSUME THERE WAS
A SECOND HIT MAN.MR. JANE, PLEASE SIT DOWN.
WERE YOU HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH KELLY FLOWER?NO.
BUT ISN'T IT TRUE
THAT YOU DELIGHT
IN KILLING SMALL FURRY ANIMALS?
YOU'RE A HUNTER.THIS IS IRRELEVANT.
OH. THIS IS
HOW WE SOLVE A MURDER.
ARE YOU SAYING YOU DON'T WANT ME
TO SOLVE A MURDER?OF COURSE I DO.
THEN ANSWER THE QUESTION, SIR.
ANSWER IT,
OR TELL ME WHY YOU WON'T.
I GO DUCK HUNTING
EVERY SEASON.
AND WHAT KIND OF GUN DO YOU USE
TO KILL THESE DEFENSELESS DUCKS?
[sighs] A 10-GAUGE SHOTGUN.
AND WOULD YOU CONSIDER YOURSELF
A VERY GOOD MARKSMAN?
UH, LAST SEASON I BAGGED
A MALLARD AT, UH, 60 YARDS.
OH, THAT'S NOT BAD.
NOT--NOT BAD AT ALL.
10-GAUGE, 3-INCH SHELL.
3 INCHES OF HELL.
3 INCHES OF DEATH.
3 1/2.
I MEAN, I THINK.
RIGHT?
SO YOU MUST BE A HUNTER, TOO.NO. I...
THEN WHAT'S THAT DEAD BEAST
IN YOUR OFFICE, MARC?
WHAT IS THAT? DID YOU JUST
GET IT OFF craigslist?
WELL, I, UH,
I MEAN, YES, I USED TO HUNT,
JUST NOT ANYMORE.
BUT YOU STILL KNOW YOUR WAY
AROUND A GUN, DON'T YOU?
OH, RELAX. IT'S NOT LOADED.
YOU OWN YOUR OWN RIFLE,
DON'T YOU?
YOU HEARD THAT THE JUDGE
HAD ISSUED A WARRANT
FOR SYLVAN'S MURDER HOUSE,
AND YOU KNEW THAT YOU HAD TO
SILENCE SYLVAN BEFORE HE TALKED.
[Rigsby] CHO, GET DOWN! \ [gunshot]
YOU HAD TO SILENCE HIM
BEFORE HE NAMED YOU
AS HIS CLIENT--
THE CLIENT WHO HIRED HIM
TO KILL KELLY FLOWER.
YOUR HONOR,
THIS IS COMPLETELY RIDICULOUS.SO PROVE IT.
LET US SEARCH YOUR HOUSE.
WE DON'T FIND A GUN,
I'LL APOLOGIZE.
LET HIM DO THE SEARCH, MARC.
NO.
NO?
I DON'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
I HAVE RIGHTS.
AND YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY
PREJUDICED AGAINST ME, JUDGE.
AND I'M GOING TO TAKE THAT UP
WITH THE CHIEF JUDGE.
IN FACT, I'M GOING
TO DO THAT RIGHT NOW.YOU SHOULD STAY PUT,
COUNSELOR. BAILIFF.
DON'T MOVE.
[Patrick whistles]
THE GUN THAT KILLED SYLVAN--
A REMINGTON 700, WITH SCOPE,
FROM YOUR GARAGE.
OH, AND, UH...
WE GOT A WARRANT. YOU'RE RIGHT.
A LOT BETTER WITH ONE OF THESE.
YOU'RE A GOOD PROSECUTOR.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS.
A SNIPER RIFLE--
LYING IN WAIT, MURDER
WITH SPECIAL CIRCUMSTANCES.
HELLO, DEATH PENALTY.
BUT IF YOU'RE WILLING TO COME
CLEAN ABOUT KELLY'S MURDER,
THE D.A. WILL TAKE DEATH
OFF THE TABLE.
THAT IS THE LAST
AND ONLY OFFER YOU'LL GET,
YOU MISERABLE SACK OF CRAP.
I REALIZED THE DRABERS
DIDN'T HIRE SYLVAN
WHEN THEY DIDN'T KILL
LISBON AND ME.
IF THEY DON'T KILL COPS,
THEY'RE CERTAINLY NOT GONNA KILL
AN ASSISTANT DISTRICT ATTORNEY.
BUT THE DRABERS WERE CONNECTED
SOMEHOW, WEREN'T THEY?
'CAUSE THEIR CASE WAS A CAREER
MAKER, ACCORDING TO KELLY,
AND YOU WANTED TO BE D.A.
SOMEDAY.
THE DRABER CASE WOULD HAVE
MADE ME A LOCK FOR D.A.
OH, YEAH.AND IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN ME.
I HAD SENIORITY. IT WAS MINE,
AND THE BITCH TOOK IT.
SO YOU HIRED SYLVAN TO KILL HER.
YES.
AND WHEN SYLVAN WAS ARRESTED,
YOU TOLD HIM YOU'D FIX IT,
THAT HE'D WALK.
AS PROSECUTOR,
YOU HAD THAT POWER.
THEN YOU HAD SYLVANTELL
HIS ATTORNEY TO INVESTIGATE ME.
THE WHOLE D.A.'s OFFICE
KNOWS HOW YOU OPERATE.
CRAZINESS.
I THOUGHT THERE WAS
A GOOD CHANCE
YOU'D STEPPED OVER
SOME LINE OR OTHER.
TURNED OUT YOU HAD.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'S LEARNED HIS LESSON.
YEAH, I HAVE.
I CERTAINLY HAVE, LISBON.
I WON'T BE STOPPING
FOR TEA AGAIN.
...AND LIGHTS OUT AT 9:30,
AND YOUR SISTER AT 9:00.
NO.
9:30.
I LOVE YOU. BYE.
[hangs up receiver]YOU WANTED TO SEE US, MA'AM?
YEAH. YEAH. SIT.
BEFORE I MAKE
ANY FINAL DECISIONS,
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
I UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU DISRUPTED A COURTROOM,
ASSAULTED AN OFFICER
OF THE COURT
SO YOU COULD QUESTION HIM
AND NEARLY CAUSED A MISTRIAL
IN AN UNRELATED FELONY CASE.
IS THAT ABOUT RIGHT?YEAH, THAT'S PRETTY ACCURATE.
YOU IGNORED YOUR SUSPENSION,
CONFRONTED A GANG OF CRIMINALS
WITHOUT ANY BACKUP
AND THEN PARTICIPATED
IN MR. JANE'S DISRUPTIONS,
ASSAULT, ETCETERA?
YES, MA'AM.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
I'M SORRY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND, MA'AM.
THE CBI JUST BUSTED
A CROOKED D.A.,
ROOTED OUT CORRUPTION AND SOLVED
THE MURDER OF ONE OF OUR OWN.AWESOME.
BY THE WAY,
I.C.E. PICKED UP THE DRABERS
AT THE CANADIAN BORDER.
THE D.A. ANNOUNCED
HE'LL TRY THE CASE HIMSELF.
WE SHOULD HAVE DONE THAT
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
I'LL TELL THE P.S.U.
TO TERMINATE YOUR SUSPENSION.
WELCOME BACK.
OH.[snaps fingers]
PATRICK,
JUDGE HILDRED'S CLERK CALLED.
YOU OWE THE COURT $16,000
IN FINES.
HE NEEDS A CASHIER'S CHECK.
[blinds rattle]
WELL,
WE CAUGHT THE BAD GUY.
YES, WE DID.
MOST DAYS, THAT'S ENOUGH.
YEP.
YOU, UH,
WANT TO GO TO THE RANGE,
SHOOT SOMETHING?
I'LL DRIVE.